Becca Nelson

Chicago, IL beccanelson.is Deccanelson **Bē** be.net/rebeccanelson

About Me

I developed an interest in technology after spending a few years as an elementary fine arts teacher. I am currently a Software Crafter at 8th Light, and love helping fellow artists and career changers understand software. My focus as a developer is on front-end design and development, where I can use my experience in design and fine arts to help designers and developers work together.

Skills

AngularJS (2+) ★★★☆ React *** HTML + CSS ★★★☆ Java (Spring) ★★★☆☆

Vue.js ★★★☆☆

Ruby + Rails ★★☆☆☆

Recent Work Experience

Software Crafter - 8th Light - Chicago, IL - November 2016—Present

- Since completing my apprenticeship, I have been developing software and consulting for multiple clients at 8th Light. Most of my time has been spent with front-end frameworks like Angular 2 and React, though I have also worked with node.js, C#, and Java.
- I am a co-chair of Diversity, Culture, and Inclusion committee, which is looking to improve company policies around diversity, specifically as they relate to the recruitment, retention, and advancement of women and minorities.

Data and Research Panelist - Ingenuity - Chicago, IL - September 2016—Present

I am serving on an advisory panel at Ingenuity, a non-profit organization that supports fine arts programs in the Chicago Public Schools. Each year, Ingenuity collects data on fine arts programs across the city, and uses that data to create an online guide called the artlook map. I have been involved in a project that is aggregating arts education data with school demographics information to learn more about arts education in Chicago.

Resident Apprentice - 8th Light - Chicago, IL - April 2016—November 2016

With guidance from two mentors, I completed a full-stack software development apprenticeship. I learned software design patterns, test-driven development, and consulting skills. I completed a pairing tour, and was evaluated at the end by a review board.

Music and Fine Arts Teacher - Various - January 2011—June 2015

Given the opportunity, I would love to tell you more about my experiences teaching both in the United States and overseas. I have taught both as a full-time teacher in one school and a traveling teaching artist at multiple schools.

Education and Training

Dev Bootcamp Completed 19-week web development program focused on full-stack Chicago, IL development, including Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, web servers, database September 2015 - January 2016 management, and courses in Engineering Empathy.

Anderson University Anderson, IN

August 2006 - May 2010

Bachelor of Music in Music Education

Anderson University Honors Program